# Margaret Macaranas

macci.webcrafterinc.com / macci@webcrafterinc.com / +63 906 518 5085 / Philippines

#### PROFILE

#### Hello, I'm Macci.

I have the well-rounded experience of building websites from planning & design, to development, to deployment & maintenance for 9 years.

I love bulding websites. I enjoy mastering coding technologies that provide websites with seamless user experience.

I've recently completed an intensive Full-Stack Web Development Training this

I have a strong design background making Front-End Development my strongest suit.

I would be more than happy to share all the skills and knowledge acquired from years of experience with your team.

#### SKILL SET

## Front-End & Full-Stack Web Develop-

Technologies used:

- HTML5, CSS3
- JavaScript, PHP
- Bootstrap, SASS
- ReactJS
- WordPress
- MySQL, MongoDB
- Laravel
- FTP, CPanel
- Software Development Life Cycle: Development, Test, Deploy
- GitLab, GitHub
- Adobe Suite (XD, Photoshop, Illustrator), Sketch

#### **Soft Skills**

Self-direction and Communication Skills

**Project Planning and Management** 

Digital Marketing (Branding, SEO, Online Ads, Universal Marketing Concepts)

Web Design and UI/UX

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## <♡/> Freelance Web Developer & Designer

Sep 2018 - Current

Developed and managed client websites, as well as their digital marketing. Aligned development and marketing with business goals.

#### Web Development

- Designed and developed visually appealing, user-friendly, and well structured websites for businesses.
- —Customized and added functionalities with CSS, JavaScript, and PHP for Wordpress.
- Ensured all features are running, e.g. e-commerce capabilities, customized dashboards, animation, SEO-optimization.
- Perform testing and troubleshooting. Deployed websites on hosting platforms (FTP, cPanel). Ensured regular backup.

#### **Management and Leadership**

- Explored client goals and structured deliverables & timelines accordingly.
- Constant communication with clients. Managed and clarified client expectations.
- Delegated and directed outsourced talents to finish project on time.

#### **Creativity and Communication**

- Oversaw branding and digital marketing. Designed brand complete visual and messaging
- Authored and implemented marketing plans. Improved businesses' online presence on all social media, ads (social media ads and Google Adwords), directories, and of course the website. Grew brand's website traffic and social media following with ads and consistent fresh content.



## **Digital Programs Lead**

ASPACE Philippines | Leading Coworking in Philippines | Jan 2016 - Sep 2017

Led the management and evolution of all digital channels especially all websites under ASPACE. Oversaw the design of programs to integrate online and anything offline.

#### Website Development, Maintenance, and Growth

- Developed and maintained the website using WordPress (Front-end, Back-end, and Admin). Ensure website achieves business objectives, is on brand, and meet UX standards. Monitored website performance. Resolved all arising techical issues.
- Set up procedures participated by the team to ensure all information on website is consistent and up-to-date in all 4 branches (Makati and Cebu).
- Introduced systems that allow customers to seamlessly book/buy products, find all public events, register to events, make payments, apply for promos, chat with live support, etc.
- Secured top ranking with SEO practices.

#### EDUCATION

#### **College Education**

#### University of Santo Tomas

College of Fine Arts and Design

- Major in Advertising Arts

#### **Key Educational Achievements**

- Dean's Lister (2007, 2008, 2009)
- Active member of Thomasian Writer's Guild (UST's official creative writing organization)

#### **Secondary Education**

St. Paul University, Quezon City

#### EXTENDED EDUCATION

#### **Zuitt Coding Bootcamp**

(Formerly Tuitt)

3-Month Intensive Full-Stack Web
Development Training

#### **Philippine Center for Creative Imaging**

- Beginnning PHP, Apache, & MySQL
- JavaScript & jQuery for Web Interactivity
- CSS Advanced Techniques and Topics

#### **First Academy of Computer Arts**

- Rich Media Design
- Web Authoring & Integration
- Web Interface Design

#### **Inventive Media**

— WordPress CMS

...Continuation from previous page

#### **Systems & Processes**

- Researched, studied, and enforced new technologies to benefit the company such as: Checkfront, Capsule CRM, NinjaForms, Event Espresso, MailChimp, Zapier, etc.
- Harmonized softwares to work together. Integrated online services to the website.
- Trained all team members of usage and best practices.

#### **Branding & Marketing**

- Implemented and tracked all online campaigns including the mechanics, distribution, and traffic. Participated heavily in brand's communications strategy.
- Made the website available for use even for the more complicated marketing campaigns (ex: 25%-off first 5 buyers, 10%-off first 20 buyers, and so on).

#### Community

- Designed and deployed booking system for wide variations of venues/products (office space, event venues, etc). The booking system is customized depending on product allowing users to book for as low as 20 mins to as much as 6 months.
- Designed and deployed registration system to handle small events to complicated international conferences both free and/or paid.
- Organized and hosted regular tech community meet-up: HackerNest Manila.



### **Digital Marketing Manager**

Gambit Technologies | WordPress Plugin Company | Sep 2017 - Sep 2018

Directed the company's marketing program. Authored market research (user demographic, behaviour, and persona; competition or market map; industry trends). Directed over-all branding — visual identity and communication strategy. Orchestrated and delivered day-to-day online campaigns, as well as campaigns for product launches, promotions, etc. Handled social media, ads, analytics, and email marketing. Improved project planning and management in office culture.



#### Senior UX/UI Designer

RMDC | Integrated Digital Marketing Firm | Nov 2014 - Dec 2015

Directed all designs for function and aesthetics of client's websites, both on desktop and on mobile. Collaborated with developers and writers to create intuitive, user-friendly websites. Redesigned and extended client's branding. Designed material for client's social media persence, ads, and content.



#### **Senior Web Designer Designer**

MetroDeal.com | #1 Group-buying Website in Philippines | Nov 2014 - Dec 2015

Designed all web materials including complete interface of e-commerce website. Designed mobile application. Facilitated all marketing and branding materials such as daily promotions and online ad campaigns (Facebook Ads, Google Ads).



#### Web & Design Specialist

Barefoot Investments / Little Green Hub | Serviced Office | Aug 2010 - Nov 2011

Oversaw company branding and collaterals for both print and web. Coordinated with client and delegated to third party talents. Managed client accounts. Conceptualized campaigns, marketing materials, including websites and online ads.

#### **Siesta Farm - Booking System**

ReactJS, MongoDB, Heroku, JavaScript, Bootstrap

**siesta-farms-booking.herokuapp.com** — Case study developing a booking system for a business providing events venue (per day) and accommodations (per night).

- Booking functionality (previously booked dates are disabled)
- Registration, Log in /out. User dashboard to check edit user detail.
- Admin dashboard for delete or update booking status (confirmed, completed, cancelled).
- Admin dashboard for editing booking details (change user, change venue, change date)

Admin Access — Username: admin@mail.com; Password: ReactJS

#### **Hotel Handler - Asset Management System**

Laravel, PHP, MySQL, Heroku, Bootstrap

<u>hotel-handler.herokuapp.com</u> — Case study building a solution for business with multiple branches to track availability, quantity, and location of assets.

- Registration, Log in /out.
- Catalog displays total quantity of a certain item the company owns. It also displays how many item is available at main branch.
- Users can request from main branch to borrow multiple items and quantity.
- Admin can approve or reject requests.

Admin Access — Username: admin; Password: javascript123

#### **THINC**

#### WordPress, Slider Revolution, HTML/CSS

**theinhouseco.com** — I developed and designed the website to playfully combine elegance and hipness. The website showcases the range of sectors our best lawyers specialise in, as well as illustrate the benefit of choosing

The website is heavily SEO-optimized.

#### **Phoenix Publishing House**

WordPress, HTML/CSS

 phoenix.com.ph — Designed with strong emphasis on the company's values: Alagang Mahalaga. Developed with a team. The website acts as a directory of hundreds of books by the publication.

Website also features a members-only section for teachers to access their resources.

#### **Estilo Decada**

Bootstrap, SASS

<u>estilodecada.com</u> — Basic website for an architectural firm showcasing my eye for design.

For more projects, feel free to visit my portfolio: macci.webcrafterinc.com

#### ABOUT ME

#### Coding

- I frequently and passionately study web development on Udemy, Team Treehouse, Youtube, printed books.

#### Goals

- To be a leading Front-End Developer in the web community
- To master JavaScript (I enjoy ReactJS)  $\,$  by building 100 websites in the next 5 years

#### Interests & Lifestyle

- I am very curious. I read a lot of non-fiction.
- $-\,\mathrm{I}$  maintain a regular yoga and meditation practice. I also just started surfing regularly.
- My parents are architects and I'm the eldest of three sisters.
- I shuffle my weeks between the city and the province.
- I'm an ENFJ. As an extrovert, I enjoy being around bright, inspiring, kind people.

#### CHARACTER REFERENCES

**Benjamin Intal** | +63 987 6543 210

(Previous Employer / CEO at Gambit Technologies)

**Micah Asistores** | +63 987 6543 210

(Previous Supervisor / Community Lead at ASPACE Philippines)

**Bernadette Dela Rosa** | +63 987 6543 210

(Previous Employer / CEO at RMDC)

**Vetch Reyes** | +63 987 6543 210

(Previous Supervisor / Deals Manager at Metrodeal.com)